

CONTACT



elise.rattigan@gmail.com



+61 (0)423 460 474



Perth, Western Australia

PROFILE

I am an experienced Project Manager and Data Scientist, currently working as an Analyst. I also have over 7 years' experience in the Pharmaceutical and Medical Communications industries.

I have a range of expertise, including SQL data modelling, data analytics and visualisation, web development and project management.

SOCIAL



github.com/EliseRattigan



in linkedin.com/in/eliserattigan



eliserattigan.com

REFERENCES

Available on request.

ELISE RATTIGAN

PROJECT MANAGER AND DATA SCIENTIST

EDUCATION

The University of Western Australia MDSc Masters of Data Science with Distinction // 2019 - 2021

- Weighted average mark of 88%
- Highest class marks in Machine Learning (99%), Data Warehousing (91%) and Introductory Analysis of Linked Health Data (89%)
- Subject areas:
 - Machine Learning with Python (Scikit-Learn, Tensorflow)
 - Data Warehousing and Relational Database Management (MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server)
 - Data Visualisation and Analysis (Tableau, PowerBI)
 - Statistics, including Bayesian Statistics and Biostatistics (R, Python, SAS)
 - Agile Web Development (HTML, CSS, Javascript, Flask, Git)

Imperial College London

BSc (Hons) Biochemistry with French for Science // 2011 - 2015

Completed Bachelor degree with Upper Second Class Honours (2:1). I spent my third year completing a research project at the University of Strasbourg, France. Alongside Biochemistry, I also studied French language and Scientific and Technical Translation.

EXPERIENCE

Deloitte, Perth

Experienced Analyst // Jan 2022 - present

- I currently work as an Experienced Analyst in Risk Advisory.
- I have gained valuable expertise in using SQL to build complex payroll models.
- On my most recent project, I stepped up to a Senior Analyst role, and my main achievements include:
 - Taking responsibility for managing three other analysts by delegating work to them, overseeing and reviewing their work, and guiding them throughout the project.
 - Becoming the go-to model expert amongst the team, using my acquired knowledge to build, debug and fix the models, while also training my team members and being the main source of information for code questions and suggestions for improvements.
 - O Developing a close relationship with the client and being regarded as the main liaison between client and data team.

SKILLS

SQL Server, MySQL

HTML / CSS / Bootstrap

Python (incl. Scikit-Learn, TensorFlow, NumPy, Pandas

Tableau

Jupyter Notebooks

Git, GitHub

Flask

Adobe InDesign

R, R Markdown

Command Line Interface

Javascript, JQuery

PowerBI

French language (quite rusty!)

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

SQL modelling
Data cleaning
Data visualisation
Testing and debugging
Machine learning
Responsive web design

MANAGEMENT SKILLS

Project management
Client relationship management
Agile methodology
Leadership
Teamwork
Effective communication

EXPERIENCE

Axiom Health, UK

Freelance Project Manager // Oct 2018 - present

I work as a remote freelancer for Axiom, managing various projects. My most recent project is the development of an online feedback portal for doctors to answer surveys about abstracts at global conferences. Built from scratch using Flask, Bootstrap and PostgreSQL. To be used at a number of future conferences and update design and functionality as required.

Epiq Global, Perth

Court Transcriber // Oct 2018 - Jan 2022

Worked part-time during my studies as a District Court transcriber, typing criminal and civil hearings, police interviews and legal inquiries. Excellent typing accuracy and speed.

Cello Health Communications, UK

Freelance Project Manager // May 2018 - Sep 2018

Worked as an in-office freelancer. Projects included:

- Taking charge of running a successful satellite symposium at a medical congress in Madrid. Managed all aspects of project from start to finish, including scientific content development, event management and liaison with client and speakers.
- Managed the day-to-day running of a global online advisor network Involved liaison with developers, crisis management, client liaison and managing junior team members.

Cube Public Relations, Sydney

Senior Account Executive // July 2017 - April 2018

Worked across several client campaigns and developed sound working relationships with health journalists and pharmaceutical clients. Managed small projects, including a medical media outreach, a journalist masterclass and a comprehensive literature review.

Cello Health Communications, UK

Project Executive // June 2015 - July 2017

Managed several projects from start to finish, including development of an online advisor network for doctors, delivery of a satellite symposium at a congress in Amsterdam, and taking charge of a large group of temps for a stakeholder mapping project.